We created a basic program that we can run on the command line.
We are using a main function here.
And we also talked about working with files.
So we worked with a cities.json file in our example here.
We need to import JSON from the standard library.
And then we can go ahead and work with this file.
Now, if we wanted to loop over each city in this list and also provide the index,
we can use the enumerate function to do that.
And remember that the using the open keyword on its own is frowned upon,
because it doesn't do any of that resource cleanup that you need to do when you're working with files.
So make sure that when you are working with files, you use a context manager.
So here, when I say with open, everything that is indented under that with statement will get sandwiched in between the code that opens the file,
and then automatically closes it and handles any exceptions without you having to wear your think about it.
When we handle exceptions, we use a try and accept block.
Here, we are accepting on a JSON decode error.
You must specific error possible for this particular exercise.
And then we can print out a specific error message as well.
Telling the user, hey, sorry, there was an error decoding that JSON file.
We talked a little bit about using the request library.
About getting a response, parsing that response that comes back in response.json.
Before you use the request library, you need to make sure that you go ahead and install it in your virtual end with pip.
Otherwise, it's an external package.
It's not part of the standard library.
So when you try to import it, if you don't have it installed, you're going to see an error.
There is some additional practice here for working with the request library that I recommend you go through on your own time.
Remember that the Python has a huge standard library with a huge number of packages.
If you want to do something, there's probably a package included.
You can use some of the more common ones in this practice.
Here we create a new file and we use the OS module.
It stands for operating system to get the current working directory.
This is another commonly used library.
You can use CIS to read command line arguments.
If you're trying to run your Python program as a script and pass in variables on the command line.
Remember that pip is the Python package index.
And it's a service that helps you find third-party Python libraries and packages.
But be mindful to type in the right thing, not have any typos because there are instances where there have been malicious packages that have lived at mis typed names.
You can search pip from the website. You can also use it on the command line as well.
And to install packages, just do Python dash and pip install requests.
That command is a little bit more verbose than just doing pip install, which you might see and other examples and tutorials.
But this guarantee is that you are using the right version of pip for your version of Python.
And I promise you it will save you lots and lots of pain.
I'm not going to cover adding tests at the moment, but tests and Python are extremely important.
So if you go back to any chapters, I recommend that you visit this one.